RESUME Kim H. Sundeen

Address:

8335 Half Moon Dr. Iron River, WI 54847 **Contact Information:**

Phone: 218-590-1330

E-mail: kim.h.sundeen@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVES

To research, plan, implement, & direct novel GIS systems, applications, and services to improve the mapping effectiveness and experience of any GIS user or non-GIS user's with understanding spatial information for personal or work projects.

EDUCATION

University of WI-Madison, WI

Professional Master of Science: Geographic Information Systems & Web Map Programming

Anticipated Completion: Summer 2018

Continuing Education

Programming

Ongoing - SQL Server Database, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, & JQuery self-taught training completed online using <u>W3schools.com</u>, <u>KhanAcademy.org</u>, & <u>Lynda.com</u>

2015 - Pennsylvania State's online self-paced course, GEOG 585, "Open Web Mapping"

2015 - WLIA Annual Conf. 4-hour workshop: "Advanced Python"

2015 - Annual Conf. MN GIS/LIS 4-hour workshops: "ArcGIS for Javascript API"

2015 - Annual Conf. MN GIS/LIS 4-hour workshops: "Using Geoprocessing Services with the ArcGIS Javascript API"

2014 - WLIA Annual Conf. 4-hour workshop: "Introduction to Python for ArcGIS 10.x"

2013 - eGIS Associates' "Introduction to the ArcGIS Javascript API Online," & "Introduction to OpenLayers," (3 days)

ArcGIS for Server & SDE Geodatabase Management

2013 - Esri's "ArcGIS for Server: Site Configuration & Administration," (3 days);

2013 - Esri's "ArcGIS for Server: Sharing GIS Content on the Web," (2 days)

2013 - Esri's "Configuring & Managing the Multiuser Geodatabase," (3 days)

University of WI-Madison, WI

Graduate Certificate: Geographic Information Systems

Aug. 2012; 3.9/4.0 GPA

Internship Focus: Spatial prediction of mercury concentration in the Great Lakes drainage basins from stream water quality data & remotely-sensed leaf area index as input for climate hydrologic models using Python & R languages.

Master of Science: Conservation Biology & Sustainable Development

December, 2011; 3.4/4.0 GPA

Thesis: Using R to model and predict sandhill crane & power line collision risk in agricultural-wetland landscapes in WI.

Bachelor of Science: Wildlife Ecology, Certificate: Environmental Studies

May, 2006; 3.2/4.0 GPA

WORK EXPERIENCE

GIS Programmer Analyst, GIS & Facility Operations, MN Power, Duluth, MN

(April 2015-Present)

Coordinated dev. & test Web AppBuilder installations; documented workflows for designing & publishing custom Survey123, Arc Collector, and WebMaps; trained staff on using Model Builder, Python, & ArcGIS Online with existing utility editing, work order, & field tools systems.

GIS Specialist, City of Duluth, Engineering Division, Duluth, MN

(Feb. 2015-April)

Coordinated full lifecycle software & database development for mapping & web data-entry applications with Python & ArcGIS Online.

GIS Specialist, Bad River Tribe, Natural Resources Dept., Odanah, WI

(Oct 2012-Feb. 2015)

Organized & designed GIS data in databases for all depts.., planned & published data-entry webmaps, & updated tribal website.

Sr. Natural Resources Research Scientist, WI Dept. of Natural Resources, Bureau of Science

Services, Madison, WI

(May 2012-Oct 2012)

Analyzed & organized water quality data for input into linear regression models using Python, ArcGIS & opensource GIS & mapping tools.

Web/GIS Technician, State Cartographer's Office, University of WI-Madison: Madison, WI

(May 2012-Oct 2012)

Customized Python scripts & add-ins to create natural basemaps of WI & updating the Cartographer's website.

GIS Project Assistant, School of Nursing, University of WI-Madison: Madison, WI

(Jan. 2010-Oct 2012)

 $Developed\ Python\ algorithms\ to\ compare\ water\ quality\ interpolated\ data\ related\ to\ how\ map\ readers\ perceived\ their\ water\ quality\ risk.$

Biologist/GIS Specialist—Student Temp. Ed. Program, US Geological Survey, Madison, WI (Oct

(Oct. 2011-May 2012)

Entered & evaluated data in one of the largest vector spatial SQL Server databases with the USFWS' National Wetlands Inventory.

PROJECT & PERSONNEL MANAGEMENT

- **Full Cycle Project Development & Implementation:** Coordinated GIS User Needs Assessment & Implementation Plans for 19 projects for software development, database development/improvements, training, & website improvements for City of Duluth IT Dept. & Public Works & Utilities Dept beginning in 2015.
- **Training:** Taught introductory Python, JavaScript, GPS & GIS sessions for small group workshops on: (1) using new mapping & GPS programs (ArcGIS 10.2.x & ArcPad 7.1-10.2), & (2) testing software including ArcGIS Desktop & opensource QGIS, (3) setting up development environments for Python & JavaScript, & (4) process for updating website front ends.
- **Staff Supervision:** Oversaw & trained student GIS technicians on GIS data entry procedures for UW Nursing School mapping projects & LTE staff for short-term land ownership projects with the Bad River Tribe.
- **Grant Writing:** Received several grants to fund M.Sc. research & provide professional development: \$10,000 from the *Animal Welfare Institute (2010)*; Additional \$1,025 from research organizations for mapping (2010-2011); \$5,200 from *ESRI for ArcMap online training through the Conservation Grant Program (2012);* \$127,000 from *the Federal Emergency Management Agency Pre-Disaster Mitigation Program.*
- **GIS Data Security:** Implemented new ArcGIS Server security protocol for publishing GIS services online; Researched & rewrote external & internal data-sharing agreements & policies for the Bad River Tribe.

DATA MANAGEMENT & PROGRAMMING KNOWLEDGE

Database & Data Structures Management:

- Awarded a **\$127,000** grant from the FEMA Pre-Disaster Mitigation Program for planning & implementing a webenabled database to deliver interactive webmaps & identify natural disaster risks for community planning meetings.
- Implemented new ArcGIS Server & published GIS secured web services for the Bad River Tribe; Expanded existing GIS map services to multiuser, versioned online feature editing & Python-built geoprocessing services for City of Duluth.
- Managed multiuser editing in ArcGIS 10.x SDE databases-2008/2013 Microsoft SQL Server for Tribe & City since 2012.

Programming:

- Created Python routines to download & extract ArcGIS Online data & images from a Survey123 app & export to a PDF with hyperlinked images and a summary of data from multiple related tables within a geodabase.
- Developed Python-based geoprocessing services to take web entry to update the SQL Server database & ArcGIS Server.
- Script opensource & ArcGIS programs to manipulate, re-write, or edit raster & vector data for use in GIS analysis & remote sensing apps (batch-processing image enhancements & transforms, & radiometric/atmospheric correction).
- Used spatial statistics & mapping programming modules in R to develop regression algorithms for predicting mercury in watersheds for drainage basins from water quality data & remotely-sensed leaf area index (LAI).

Web Development:

- Developed, tested, trained staff, & implemented customized GIS services & geoprocessing tools through ArcGIS Server for mobile data entry & data-transfer through ArcGIS Online webmaps for the Tribe, City of Duluth, & MN Power.
- Added new HTML/CSS pages for reorganizing the Bad River Tribal Natural Resources webpage to host both secured & public Google, Esri JavaScript API, ArcGIS Online, & GeoMoose OpenLayers webmaps: www.badriver-nsn.gov/tribal-operations/natural-resources/gis-maps

SOFTWARE

Databases: Microsoft (SQL Server 2008/2013, SQL Server Express, & MS Access), Oracle Spatial, ArcSDE & PostgreSQL **GIS/GPS:** ArcGIS 9.3-10.3.1., ArcGIS Pro, QGIS 1.6-2.16, Google Earth, ArcPad 7.1 & 10.2, Terrasync 5.6, & Pathfinder Office 5.4 **Statistics/Remote Sensing:** ENVI, IDRISI, R, SPSS, Systat, S-PLUS, OpenEV, Opticks

Programming: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python (Arcpy, OGR, GDAL, & modules) for object-oriented programming, Github & SVN **Code Versioning:** TortoiseShell SVN, Github

Presentation/Design: Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop 2015.5; & Microsoft 7 & 10 OS Office, Prezi, Slides.com, reveal.js

Project Management: Basecamp, MindManager, Freedcamp, Windows OneNote

Web Content Management Systems: Joomla, Druple, WordPress, Bluehost

VOLUNTEER POSITIONS

MN GIS/LIS Conference Planning Team: *St. Paul, MN*Wember; Workshop Planning Committee
WI Land Information Association: *Madison, WI*National Tribal Geog. Info. Support Center: *Albuquerque, NM*Board Member; Chair Membership Committee
Publications Committee Member
2015-Present
Publications Committee Member
2013-2014

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Geocaching, Birding, Canoeing, Skiing, Piano, Jazz music, Singing Phantom of the Opera songs

Please see my website www.sunnyspace.org/kimsundeen

Resume—Kim Sundeen Page 2

Resume—Kim Sundeen Page 3